Guide to the Leonard Leopold Mackall Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Leonard Leopold Mackall papers
1919-1938
MS 1325
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
The papers consist of correspondence, clippings, booklets of Leonard L. Mackall. The bulk of the correspondence is with John F. Fulton.
Mackall, Leonard L. (Leonard Leopold), 1879-1937
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Yale University Historical Medical Library, 1980.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Leonard Leopold Mackall was born on January 29, 1879, in Baltimore, Maryland. He received his bachelor's degree from Johns Hopkins University in 1900 where he took an interest in German literature. In 1902, he graduated from Harvard Law School. Within the next few years, he would attend Johns Hopkins University and the Universities of Berlin and Jena. Mackall was known for being an avid book collector and bibliographer. He wrote a column for bibliophiles in the New York Herald Tribune and was president of the Georgia Historical Society and the Bibliographical Society of America. Mackall died on May 19, 1937, in Fredericksburg, Virginia.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, clippings, booklets of Leonard L. Mackall. The bulk of the correspondence is with John F. Fulton.
Medicine; Mackall, Leonard L. (Leonard Leopold), 1879-1937
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1924-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - John F. Fulton and Mackall [bound volume], 1924-1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - About Mackall, 1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Writings
    - Reprints and newspaper articles [bound volume], 1919-1931, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Additional writings, 1920-1928, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Tributes
    - Bound volume, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Loose, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)